舰长日志，星历1312.4
Captain's log, stardate 1312.4.
不可思议的事情发生了
The impossible has happened.
我们收到正前方发出的遇难录音信号
From directly ahead, we're picking up a recorded distress signal,
来自一艘二百多年前失踪的星舰
the call letters of a vessel which has been missing for over two centuries.
在我们之前，还有别的人类飞船探索过银河系之外吗？
Did another Earth ship once probe out of the galaxy, as we intend to do?
他们在那里遭遇了什么？
what happened to it out there?
这是他们留下的警示吗？
Is this some warning they've left behind?
到你了，舰长
Your move, captain.
现在我们应该到达了拦截的位置，舰桥说他们会呼叫我们
We should've intercepted by now. The bridge said they'd call.
下一步我就要将死你了
I'll have you checkmated your next move.
史波克，你的棋品让人恼火啊
Have I ever mentioned you play a very irritating game of chess, Mr. Spock?
恼火？
Irritating?
是啊，一种人类情绪
Oh, yes, one of your Earth emotions.
你真的不理解恼火？
Certain you don't know what irritation is?
实际上，我有位祖先娶了一位人类女性
In fact, one of my ancestors married a human female.
可怕吧，继承了这样的血统
Terrible, having bad blood like that.
舰桥呼叫休息室
Bridge to Briefing Lounge.
目标进入牵引光束范围
Object is now within tractor-beam range.
科尔索先生，没有视像联系吗？
No visual contact, Mr. Kelso?
没有，长官，作为一艘船来说它太小了
No, sir. It’s too small to be a vessel.
直径大约一米
It only reads about 1 meter in diameter.
比救生艇还小
Not large enough even for a lifeboat.
长官，这个大小可以传送到船上，如果你愿意冒险的话
Small enough to bring it aboard, sir, if you wanna risk it.
科尔索先生，锁定它
Lock onto it, Mr. Kelso.
- 长官，物化已就绪 - 传过来
- Materializer ready, sir. - Bring it aboard.
老式舰船记录器
Old-style ship recorder.
当舰船受威胁时可以把它弹射出去
They could be ejected when something threatened the ship.
似乎是毁灭性的威胁
More like destroyed the ship, in this case.
你看，到处是烧痕和坑…
Look at it. Burnt, pitted...
但愿资料完好无损
Let's hope its tapes are intact.
把记录传入史波克的电脑
We'll feed it through Mr. Spock's computer.
遵命，长官
Yes, sir.
长官，传送开始
It's begun transmitting, sir.
通知舰桥，全舰戒备
Flash the bridge. Put all decks on the alert.
宇宙，最后的边疆
Space, the final frontier.
这是星舰进取号的航程
These are the voyages Of the starship Enterprise.
它的五年任务，是去探索未知的新世界
Its five-year mission: To explore strange new worlds,
找寻新的生命与新的文明
to seek out new life and new civilisations,
勇敢的航向前人未至之境
to boldly go where no man has gone before.
【星际迷航：原初】
-=THE LAST FANTASY=-
荣誉出品
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业途径
-=TLF字幕组=-
翻译：马田的心事，kmdangdangli，Nick
校对：喜马拉雅，Micezhang，xjCGI
第一季第三集
前人未至之境
- 等等，吉姆 - 准备好了吗？
- Hold it, Jim. - Getting into shape?
是，我猜你不在舰桥上
Yeah, well, I figured you weren't on the bridge.
科尔索听上去有点紧张
Kelso's voice sounded a little nervous.
棋下完了？
Well, you finish the game?
嗯，他的棋路完全不合逻辑
He played most illogically.
他下一步应该出车
His next move should have been the rook.
奥尔登先生，换班时间到
You're relieved, Mr. Alden.
好的，米歇尔先生
Acknowledged, Mr. Mitchell.
屏显
Screen on.
屏显，长官
Screen on, sir.
正在接近银河边缘
Approaching galaxy edge, sir.
米歇尔先生，退出曲速，保持在这个位置
Neutralise warp, Mr. Mitchell. Hold this position.
长官，已经退出曲速
Neutralise warp, sir.
- 开启内部广播 - 内部广播已开启
- Address intercraft. - Intercraft open.
我是舰长
This is the captain speaking.
我们捕获了一艘船的遇难记录器
The object we encountered is a ship's disaster recorder,
应该是从两百年前的星舰勇士号上弹射出的
apparently ejected from the s.s. Valiant almost 200 years ago.
记录磁带烧毁了，正在尝试分析记忆资料库
The tapes are burned out. Trying the memory banks.
我们希望能找到勇士号对该区域的记录
We hope to learn from the recorder what the Valiant was doing here
并找出事故的罪魁祸首
and what destroyed the vessel.
一旦搞清楚我们就会继续探索
We'll move out into our probe as soon as we have those answers.
- 全舰待命 - 长官，部门主管报道
- All decks stand by. - Our department heads, sir.
你要他们在星舰离开银河系之前都留在舰桥的
You wanted everybody on the bridge before we left the galaxy.
当然
Yes.
- 琼斯 - 长官，我是史密斯
- Jones. - Name's Smith, sir.
天体科学部现已就绪
Astroscience is standing by, captain.
工程部一如既往地随时待命
Engineering Division ready, as always.
生命科学部也已就绪
Life Sciences ready, sir.
这位是德纳医生，在毕宿五殖民地加入进取号
This is Dr. Dehner, who joined the ship at the Aldebaran colony.
精神病理学，舰长
Psychiatry, captain.
我的任务是研究船员在紧急情况下的反应
My assignment is to study crew reaction in emergency conditions.
现在从记录器中得到一些信息
Getting something from the recorder now.
如果是突发状况
If there was an emergency,
我很想研究一下舰员的反应
I'd be interested in how that crew reacted too.
医生，改良物种也是你的任务吗？
Well, improving the breed, doctor? Is that your line?
据说那是你的专业，中校
I heard that's more your specialty, commander.
当然也是你的专长
Line included.
冰山美人啊
A walking freezer unit.
正在解码记忆资料库，稍后进行破译
Decoding memory banks. I'll try to interpolate.
勇士号曾遭遇太空磁暴
The Valiant had encountered a magnetic space storm
之后被吹向这个方向
and was being swept in this direction.
老式脉冲引擎推力不够
The old impulse engines weren't strong enough.
舰船被推到了银河系外约半光年处
Swept past this point about a half light-year out of the galaxy.
他们被抛了出去，然后掉头回到这里
They were thrown clear, turned and headed back into the galaxy here.
我只读到些片段，记录磁带严重烧毁
I'm not getting it all. The tapes are pretty badly burned.
听起来像是舰船遇到了未知力量
Sounds like the ship had encountered some unknown force.
然后，命令…抵制命令…
Now...orders, counter-orders.
反复发出紧急指令
Repeated urgent requests for information
要求舰船电脑调出
from the ship's computer records
与人类超感知觉有关的所有信息
for anything concerning ESP in human beings.
超感知觉？
Extrasensory perception?
德纳博士，你在超感知觉方面怎么样？
Dr. Dehner, how are you on ESP?
我在超感知觉测试中得了高分
In tests I've taken, my ESP rated rather high.
我问你对超感知觉了解多少？
I'm asking what you know about ESP.
事实上有些人能感知未来
It is a fact that some people can sense future happenings,
或是从扑克牌的背面读牌之类
read the backs of playing cards, and so on.
但是超感者的能力十分有限
But the ESPer capacity is always quite limited.
严重受损，七名舰员身亡
Severe damage. Seven crewmen dead.
不，是六个
No, make that six.
有一名舰员似乎恢复了
One crewman seemed to have recovered.
从这时起他们开始关注超感知觉
That's when they became interested in extrasensory perception.
不是一般的关注，简直是发了疯
More than interested. Almost frantic about it.
不，我肯定是理解有误
No, this must be garbled.
我听到了“自毁”之类的命令
I get something about "destruct."
我肯定是听错了
I must've read it wrong.
听起来像是舰长下令自毁舰船
It sounded like the captain giving an order to destroy his own ship.
有什么看法吗？
Comments?
唯一能确定的
The only fact we have for sure
是勇士号被毁了
is that the s.s. Valiant was destroyed.
为此我们必须继续这次探险
Which is probably the best argument to continue the probe.
将来还有别的飞船到达
Other vessels will be heading out here someday,
这样他们就能提前有所防备
and they'll have to know what they'll be facing.
米歇尔先生，准备离开银河系
We're leaving the galaxy, Mr. Mitchell.
向前飞行，一级曲速
Ahead, warp factor 1.
- 探测到某种力场 - 我们即将进入该力场
- Forcefield of some kind. - And we're coming up on it fast.
- 开启传感器 - 长官，传感器已开启
- Sensor beam on. - Sensor beam on, sir.
- 偏转器全开 - 偏转器已全开
- Deflectors, full intensity. - Deflectors, full intensity.
偏转器显示此处有东西，传感器没有反应
Deflectors say there's something there. Sensors say there isn't.
零密度，零辐射
Density: negative. Radiation: negative.
没有能量
Energy: negative.
不管它是什么，十二秒后正面接触
Whatever it is, contact in 1 2 seconds.
调成自动引力系统
Gravitation on automatic.
急救中心，拉响全舰火警警报
Emergency stations. All decks on fire alert.
科尔索，停止自动控制，改为手动操作
Neutralise controls. Kelso, put it on manual.
- 有辐射之类的吗？ - 没有
- Any radiation? Anything? - Negative.
舵手，离开此处
Helmsman, take us out of here.
舵手
Helmsman!
侧面推力
Lateral power!
提交损坏报告
Take damage reports.
所有岗位，提交损坏报告
Damage-control reports, all stations.
重力控制系统转换为备用能源
Gravity control switching to batteries.
有东西击中了我
Something hit me.
像是电击
Like an electrical charge.
他还活着，只是被击昏了
He's alive. Appears to be in shock.
三层甲板工程部，能否提交损坏报告？
Engineering Deck 3. Can you give a damage report?
切断传感光束，偏转器功率全开
Cut the sensor beams. Full power on the deflectors.
长官，主引擎离线，现已启用应急备用能源
Main engines are out, sir. We're on emergency power cells.
- 九名舰员身亡 - 重力值降至0.8
- Casualties: nine dead. - Gravity is down to 0.8.
全船注意，这里是舰桥工程部，进入三级戒备
All decks, this is Bridge Engineering. Go to emergency condition three.
加里？
Gary?
加里，你还好吧？
Gary, you all right?
吉姆，不知道怎么了，我有些发虚，但是…
I'm a little weak for some reason, Jim, but...
…现在感觉好多了
...I feel all right now.
舰长日志，星历1312.9
Captain's log, stardate 1312.9.
舰船目前只能靠脉冲动力返回星系
Ship's condition: heading back on impulse power only.
主引擎烧毁
Main engines: burned out.
无法进行曲速飞行
The ship's space-warp ability: gone.
几天便能到达的地球基地
Earth bases, which were only days away,
现在需要几年
are now years in the distance.
目前我们最关心的问题是，究竟是什么摧毁了勇士号？
Our overriding question now is what destroyed the Valiant?
像我们一样，他们从死亡线上侥幸逃脱
They lived through the barrier, just as we have.
之后他们遭遇了什么？
what happened to them after that?
（伊丽莎白·德纳博士）
（超感知能力等级高于平均水平…选择成为心理医生…）
（加里·米歇尔上尉）
（超感知能力等级异常高于平均水平…）
长官，验尸报告
Autopsy report, sir.
每具尸体的神经回路都受到了损坏
Each case showed damage to the body's neural circuit.
大脑中的某个区域被烧毁
An area of the brain was burned out.
- 你呢，一切正常？ - 很好，米歇尔也是
- And you? Are you feeling all right? - Yes. Mitchell too.
除了他的眼睛
Except for his eyes.
我们正在检查原因
We're trying to find a reason for that now,
以及为什么只有一部分舰员受到了影响
and why, out of our whole crew, only certain people were affected.
医生，我认为答案很简单
I think we've found that answer, doctor.
你曾说那些测试
You mentioned that tests show
表明你有很高的超感知觉能力
that you have a high degree of extrasensory perception.
其它舰员也是
So do the records of the others.
加里·米歇尔的得分最高
Gary Mitchell has the highest ESPer rating of all.
如果你在暗示我很危险…
If you're suggesting there's anything dangerous--
勇士号被摧毁之前
Before the Valiant was destroyed,
舰长曾疯狂搜寻舰员的超感知觉信息
its captain was frantically searching for ESP information on his crew.
超感者不过是能心灵感应的普通人
ESPers are simply people with flashes of insight.
有的人还能透视固体
Are there not also those who seem to see through solid objects,
令物体自燃呢
cause fires to start spontaneously?
这不足以让超感知觉者成为危险份子
There's nothing about it that could possibly make a person dangerous.
德纳医生指的是普通的超感知觉能力
Dr. Dehner is speaking of normal ESP power.
也许你知道不一般的
Perhaps you know of another kind.
医生，我们真的能够肯定，当真没有其它类型吗？
Do we know for sure, doctor, that there isn't another kind?
（呼吸  脉搏）
你好，吉姆
Hello, Jim.
你满面愁容啊
Hey, you look worried.
自从天津四的那晚开始我就一直担心你
I've been worried about you ever since that night on Deneb IV.
对啊，那是颗新星
Yeah, she was nova, that one.
这次没那么多后遗症了
Not nearly as many after-effects this time.
除了眼睛
Except for the eyes.
刮胡子的时候我老觉得它们盯着我
They kind of stare back at me when I'm shaving.
感觉哪里不对劲吗？
Do you feel any different?
在某种程度上，现在再好不过了
Well, in a way, I feel better than I've ever felt before in my life.
其实还获益匪浅
Actually seems to have done me some good.
怎么讲？
How?
我总算有机会拜读那些你最爱的大部头
Well, I'm getting a chance to read some of that long-hair stuff you like.
伙计，我还记得你在星舰学院那会儿
Hey, man, I remember you back at the Academy:
你就是个移动图书馆
A stack of books with legs.
学长们对我说的第一件事就是
The first thing I ever heard from an upperclassman was,
小心寇克上尉，在他的课上要么思考要么绝望
"Watch out for Lieutenant Kirk. In his class, you either think or sink."
没那么糟糕吧
I wasn't that bad, was I?
要不是我看上了那个金发小美女研究员…
If I hadn't aimed that little blond lab technician at you...
什么？你计划好的？
You what? You planned that?
你不是想让我思考吗？
Well, you wanted me to think, didn't you?
我对她发起了攻势
I outlined her whole campaign for her.
我差点就娶了她
I almost married her.
最好对我好点
Better be good to me.
在病房里我都比你聪明
I'm getting even better ideas here.
你？斯宾诺沙[哲学家]？
You? Spinoza?
一旦你研究他就会发现他有些单纯，可以说是幼稚
Once you get into him, he's rather simple, though. Childish, almost.
- 我完全不能同意他的看法 - 继续说
- I don't agree with him at all. - Go on.
嘿…我是说我好多了，什么时候复职？
Hey, I'm trying to tell you I feel fine. When do I go back on duty?
我得让德纳医生再观察你一段时间
I'm gonna ask Dr. Dehner to keep you under observation for a while.
船上这么多女的
With almost 100 women on board,
你就不能换个人，亲爱的舰长？
you can do better than that, friend captain.
就当是个挑战吧
Consider it a challenge.
这可不够朋友
That doesn't seem very friendly.
我是否说过你最好…
Didn't I say you'd better...
对我好点？
...be good to me?
他的阅读速度又变快了
He's reading faster now than just a few moments ago.
他还是你认识的加里·米歇尔吗？
Is that Gary Mitchell, the one you used to know?
24小时监视医务室
Put a 24-hour watch on Sickbay.
从头到脚把他检查一遍
Fullest possible range of examinations and tests.
好极了
Perfect, perfect.
我从未遇过你这样的病人，加里
I've never had a patient like you, Gary.
再健康的人都有些小毛病
Even the healthiest are generally off on some reading.
你一直反感我，米歇尔上尉
I know you don't particularly like me, Mr. Mitchell,
何不既来之则安之？
but since I am assigned here, can we make the best of it?
我可没反感你，大夫
I've got nothing against you, doctor.
你说我冷若冰霜
Nor against the "walking freezer unit"?
对此我很抱歉
Well, sorry about that.
女人都擅长钻牛角尖
Women professionals do tend to overcompensate.
聊聊你吧，你好些了吗？
Now, let's talk about you. How do you feel?
怎么大家都忧心忡忡
You know, everybody seems worried
似乎要我生个病才放心
that I don't have some kind of a fever or something.
也许得改改这些指针
Maybe if I could just change these dials...
还是恢复原样吧
Now back to normal, I think.
你是怎么做到的？
How did you do that?
我也不清楚，我…
I'm not sure. I...
我才这么想，指针就动了
I just thought of making it happen, and it does. It just...
嘿…
Hey...
嘿…瞧我的，大夫
Hey, watch this, doc.
快别闹了
Stop it. Stop it.
你死过去22秒，没有任何生命迹象
You were dead for almost 22 seconds. There were no readings at all.
是啊
Yeah.
哇噢…
Oh, boy...
大夫，我能做的还不止这些
You know, doc, there have been other things too.
不出一天我就能读完半个图书馆
Like going halfway through the ship's library in hardly a day.
是啊
Yeah.
我这是怎么了？
What's happening to me?
读这么快，你还能过目不忘？
Do you remember everything you read that quickly?
是的
Yeah.
任何一盘带子？
On any tape?
千真万确
Sure. Yeah.
试试这盘
Try this one.
好
Yeah.
387页
Page 387.
我的爱似飞鸟的双翼
My love has wings
婀娜轻盈的羽毛
Slender, feathered things
如此优雅，妙曼
with grace and upswept curve And tapered tip
《夜莺般的女子》
"Nightingale Woman."
作者塔尔博德，写于老人星，1996年
Written by Tarbolde on the Canopus Planet back in 1996.
你选的诗真有趣，大夫
It's funny you picked that one, doctor.
此话怎讲？
Why?
这是过去几个世纪
That's one of the most passionate love sonnets
最富激情的爱情短诗
of the past couple of centuries.
你觉得如何，大夫？
How do you feel, doctor?
- 什么？- 觉得如何？
- What? - How do you feel?
你弄疼我了，没别的
I just fell. Nothing happened.
你确定？
Are you sure?
我正要喝咖啡，顺便过来看看…
I was on my coffee break. I thought I'd check up on--
是吗？
Yeah.
没事的，李，进来吧
That's okay, Lee. Come on in.
不用担心我发光的双眼，伙计
Don't let the light in my eyes bother you, pal.
这位美女大夫，点亮了我的双眼
It's all for our good-looking lady doctor here.
- 是啊 - 维修进展如何？
- Yeah, sure. - So how go the repairs?
嗯…主引擎坏了
Well, the main engines are gone,
除非我们找到方法重新维修
unless we can find some way to reenergize them.
你最好去检查一下右舷的脉冲动力组
You better check the starboard impulse packs.
那些重要的节点已经衰退了
Those points have about decayed to lead.
- 哦…别说笑了，米歇尔 - 我没开玩笑，李！
- Oh, yeah, sure, Mitch. - I'm not joking, Lee!
一旦激活那些动力组，整个脉冲引擎舱会炸个稀烂
You activate those packs, and you'll blow the whole impulse deck.
我立刻就去查
I'll get on it right away.
我就是来看看你，一会儿见
I just wanted to stop by and make sure you were okay. See you later.
他真笨
He's a fool.
一个蠢货
A fool.
他检查过那些节点，却没有发现问题
He'd seen those points, and he hadn't noticed their condition.
你是怎么知道的？
How do you know?
他看到的一切，还映在他脑里
The image of what he'd seen was still in his mind.
他不可能知道
Well, it didn't make any sense that he'd know,
可我还是检查了线路
but naturally, I checked out the circuit anyway.
还真被他说中了
I don't know how, but he was right.
这个节点已经被烧毁了，和他说的一模一样
This point is burned out exactly the way he described it.
对不起，我来迟了
Sorry I'm late.
我忙着观察加里…米歇尔上尉
I became so interested in observing Gary-- Mr. Mitchell.
对方不再是加里·米歇尔
Our subject is not Gary Mitchell.
我更担心他会变异成什么
Our concern is, rather, what he is mutating into.
我知道你们的星球
I know those from your planet
不像我们感情用事，史波克先生
aren't supposed to have feelings like we do, Mr. Spock,
但这么讲一个和你共事多年的人也太没…
but to talk that way about a man you've worked next to for years is worse than--
- 够了，大夫 - 让我说完
- That's enough, doctor. - I don't think so.
我最想不通的是你
I understand you least of all.
加里服役时，你们就是朋友
Gary told me that you've been friends since he joined the service,
你第一个命令，就是让他登舰
that you asked for him aboard your first command.
不管是否愿意，我的职责
It is my duty, whether pleasant or unpleasant,
就是听取汇报，观察，甚至推测
to listen to the reports, observations, even speculations,
任何威胁星舰安全的事物
on any subject that might affect the safety of this vessel.
作为科学官，需要服从我的命令
And it's my science officer's duty to see that I'm provided with that.
接着说，史波克大副
Go ahead, Mr. Spock.
他有哪些特异功能？
Have you noted evidence of unusual powers?
他能支配某些自主反射神经
He can control certain autonomic reflexes.
他的阅读速度极快
He reads very fast.
记忆力超常
Retains more than most of us might consider usual.
史考特先生，你能把之前告诉我们的事情重复一遍吗？
Mr. Scott, would you repeat what you just told us?
一小时前，舰桥控制室出现异常
About an hour ago, the bridge controls started going crazy.
操纵杆自己动起来，按钮会自己按下去
Levers shifting by themselves, buttons being pushed,
显示器读数一直在变
instrument readings changing.
监视屏显示，每次异常，米歇尔都面露微笑
And on my monitor screen, I could see Mitchell smiling each time it happened,
似乎星舰和队员成了他的玩具
as if this ship and crew were almost a toy for his amusement.
他们说得对吗，大夫？
Are they right, doctor?
他有这么大能耐？
Has he shown abilities of such magnitude?
是有一些迹象
I saw some such indications.
可你却知而不报？
You didn't think it worth mentioning?
他没伤害任何人，你们不明白吗？
No one's been hurt, have they? Don't you understand?
变异令他能力超凡，这也许是件好事
A mutated superior man could also be a wonderful thing.
预示着更为出色的新人类！
The forerunner of a new and better kind of human being!
你怎么看，苏鲁？
Mr. Sulu.
从数学的角度来看
If you want the mathematics of this,
米歇尔的能力，正呈几何级数增长
Mitchell's ability is increasing geometrically.
就像一便士，每天翻一番的话
That is like having a penny, doubling it every day.
一个月你就是百万富翁
In a month, you'll be a millionaire.
不出一个月
In less time than that,
他将会获得我们不了解和无法与之对抗的能力
he will have attained powers we can't understand and can't cope with.
很快他会觉得，我们一无是处
Soon, we'll be not only useless to him,
甚至碍手碍脚
but actually an annoyance.
这些谈话必须保密
There'll be no discussion of this with the crew.
散会
Thank you.
只要他在，就别想抵达地球基地
We'll never reach an Earth base with him aboard, Jim.
数学计算的结果你也听到了
You heard the mathematics of it.
不出一月，我们在他眼里
In a month, he'll have as much in common with us
就是一船小白鼠
as we'd have with a ship full of white mice.
我要实际方案，不是口头警告
What I need are recommendations, Spock, not vague warnings.
方案一
Recommendation one:
织女四离这几光年，不日便可抵达
There's a planet a few light-days away from here, Delta Vega.
那里有座锂元素裂化工厂
It has a lithium-cracking station.
我们可以改造那里的动力装置给星舰的引擎使用
We may be able to adapt some of its power packs to our engines.
如果失败，就会陷在那的轨道上
And if we can't, we'll be trapped in orbit there.
我们没有足够的动力挣脱轨道
We haven't enough power to blast back out.
可只有这样，才能摆脱米歇尔
It is the only possible way to get Mitchell off this ship.
把他扔那，我可做不到
If you mean strand Mitchell there, I won't do it.
工厂全部自动化，连个鬼影都没有
The station is fully automated. There's not a soul on the whole planet.
采矿船20年才去一次
Even the ore ships call only once every 20 years.
你还有另一个选择
Then you have one other choice:
现在就杀了米歇尔
Kill Mitchell while you still can.
- 出去 - 除此之外，你别无选择
- Get out of here. - It is your only other choice.
现在似乎还为时不晚
Assuming you make it while you still have time.
你就不能有点人情味？
Will you try for one moment to feel?
毕竟你也有颗跳动的心
At least act like you've got a heart.
我们说的可是加里
We're talking about Gary.
勇士号的舰长，估计也和你一样
The captain of the Valiant probably felt the same way.
他的感情用事断送了整艘星舰
And he waited too long to make his decision.
这点你我都清楚
I think we've both guessed that.
调整航线，前往织女四
Set course for Delta Vega.
星历1313.1
Stardate 1313.1.
我们正在接近织女四，设定航线进入标准轨道
we're now approaching Delta Vega. Course set for a standard orbit.
该行星完全无人居住，体积略小于地球
This planet, completely uninhabited, is slightly smaller than Earth.
荒僻，但是富含晶体及矿藏
Desolate, but rich in crystal and minerals.
科尔索和维修小组一起传送下去
Kelso's task: transport down with a repair party,
尝试更新主引擎，挽救这艘星舰
try to regenerate the main engines, save the ship.
我们则要押送一个我认识15年的人…
Our task: transport down a man I've known for 15 years...
…如果成功，那便是他的流放地
...and if we're successful, maroon him there.
我渴了
I'm thirsty.
就像瞎了一辈子的人
It's like a man who has been blind all of his life
突然重获光明
suddenly being given sight.
有时我觉得自己可以无所不能
Sometimes I feel there's nothing I couldn't do, in time.
我是不是被当成了怪物，吉姆？
Some people think that makes me a monster, don't they, Jim?
你能洞悉我们的心思？
Are you reading all our thoughts, Gary?
吉姆，我知道你最担心的
I can sense mainly worry in you, Jim.
是星舰的安危
Safety of your ship.
换了你会怎么做？
What would you do in my place?
也许是史波克现在想的
Probably just what Mr. Spock is thinking now.
杀了我，趁现在
Kill me while you can.
住手，加里！
Stop it, Gary!
我还知道，我们正在织女四的轨道上，吉姆
I also know we're orbiting Delta Vega, Jim.
你别想带我到那里去
I can't let you force me down there.
现在还不是时候
I may not wanna leave the ship, not yet.
还有更适合我的地方
I may want another place.
我还不知道如何支配这个世界
I'm not sure yet just what kind of a world I can use.
支配？
Use?
目前我还不确定
I don't understand it all yet,
等我变得更强大
but if I keep growing, getting stronger,
也许我就能
why, the things I could do...
成为…成为万能的神
Like maybe a god could do.
把他弄晕
I want him unconscious for a while.
一群蠢货！我要像拍苍蝇那样杀死你们！
You fools! Soon I'll squash you like insects!
传送
Energize.
能成吗，李？
Can you do it, Lee?
也许能，只要我们绕过燃料箱的时候不被炸飞
Maybe, if we can bypass the fuel bins without blowing ourselves up.
把他带走
Take him.
这儿除了我们真的没有别人了吗？
There's not a soul on this planet but us?
就我们这帮人，大夫
Nobody but us chickens, doctor.
找到203-R组件了，李
I think I got the 203-R set, Lee.
很好，奥尔登，你负责把它带回去
Good, Alden. Transport it up with you, will you?
李，能在这引爆那些燃料箱吗？
The fuel bins, Lee, could they be detonated from here?
用引爆开关
A destruct switch?
估计开关可以安在这儿
I guess I could wire one up right there.
- 快安 - 他快醒了
- Do it. - He's regaining consciousness.
派珀医生
Dr. Piper...
让一名医疗官守在这，寸步不离
...I want only one medical officer here at any one time.
另一名用监视器监视他
The other will monitor him on the dispensary screen.
让我待在这和他说说话
I'd like to stay now, try to talk to him.
詹姆士·寇克，我的朋友
My friend, James Kirk.
还记得蒂莫罗斯星上
Remember those rodent things on Dimorus,
那些会喷毒箭的大老鼠吗？
the poisoned darts they threw?
我为你挡了一记
I took one meant for you.
还险些丧了命
And almost died.
- 当然记得 - 那现在你为什么会怕我？
- I remember. - So why be afraid of me now?
因为你正在尝试用超能力接管进取号
You've been testing your ability to take over the Enterprise.
在传送室里
In the Transporter Room, you said something
你将我们比作蝼蚁
about us seeming like insects by comparison,
如果有人碍事就碾碎我们
squashing us if we got in your way.
我被打了麻药
I was drugged then.
没错
Yes.
在医务室里，你说如果你是舰长
In the Sickbay, you said if you were in my place,
你就会杀死像你这样的变种人
you'd kill a mutant like yourself.
那你怎么不动手？
Why don't you kill me, then?
傻子都能看出来，史波克先生是对的
Mr. Spock is right, and you're a fool if you can't see it.
别这么说，加里
You don't mean that, Gary.
如果真正的超感人诞生了，人类将会灭亡
Man cannot survive if a race of true ESPers is born.
很快你就会知道
In time, you'll understand that.
加里，别！
Gary, don't!
吉姆…
Jim...
他的眼睛恢复正常了
His eyes went back to normal.
对抗力场剥夺了他的力量
Fighting the forcefield drained his strength.
暂时他无力反抗了
For a while, at least. He could be handled now.
我会不断地变强
I'll just keep getting stronger.
你知道的，对吧？
You know that, don't you?
那部件就像是定做的，舰长
It fits like a glove, captain.
史波克收到我们送去的相位步枪了吗？
Did Mr. spock get the phaser rifle we sent down?
我并没有下令…
I didn't order any...
收到了，外遣队通讯完毕
Affirmative. Landing party out.
他又试图穿越力场了
He tried to get through the forcefield again.
而他的眼睛变化得更快了，几乎毫发无损
His eyes changed faster. He didn't become as weak.
德纳医生并不认为他很危险
Dr. Dehner feels he isn't that dangerous.
难道你是对的，职业医生却错了？
What makes you right and a trained psychiatrist wrong?
因为她感情用事，而我不会
Because she feels. I don't.
我的思考符合逻辑
All I know is logic.
在我看来，我们最好尽快修好这艘船，然后离开这里
In my opinion, we'll be lucky if we can repair this ship and get away in time.
这里直接与燃料箱相连
Direct to the power bins.
你可以在这里把整个山谷炸毁
From here, you could blow up this whole valley.
如果米歇尔逃出来了…
If Mitchell gets out...
李，如果你在这里，并且认为已别无选择…
At your discretion, Lee, if sitting here, you think you're the last chance...
…我要你按下那个按钮
...I want you to hit that button.
舰长日志，星历1313.3
Captain's log, stardate 1313.3.
赞扬科尔索上尉和工程人员们
Note commendations on Lieutenant Kelso and the Engineering staff.
进取号正在我们头顶上的轨道运行
In orbit above us, the engines of the Enterprise
引擎几乎已经完全恢复
are almost fully regenerated.
剩下的大部分外遣队正被传送回舰
Balance of the landing party is being transported back up.
米歇尔，不论他将变成什么样
Mitchell, whatever he's become,
他都会一直蜕变，每一分钟都在变得更强
keeps changing, growing stronger by the minute.
这几个小时他一直是那个样
He's been like that for hours now.
让派珀医生与我们和科尔索在控制室汇合
Have Dr. Piper meet us in the control room with Kelso.
我们一起传送回飞船
We'll all transport up together.
如果他企图阻止我们呢？
If he should try to stop us?
科尔索会随时准备按下那个按钮
Kelso will be on the destruct button until the last minute.
他知道应该怎么做
I think he knows that.
我要和他一起留下来
I'm staying behind with him.
第三裂变室检查完毕，运作正常
Fission chamber three checks out. The station seems to be running fine.
科尔索，你不当小偷真可惜
You're a talented thief, Kelso.
你送上来的所有零件都非常合适
Everything you sent up seems to be fitting in place.
我们对自己的工作很自豪
I'm kind of proud of the job we've done.
是不是已经准备好要传送…
Are we gonna be ready to transport--?
- 你要和这艘船一起走，医生 - 他并不邪恶
- You're leaving with the ship, doctor. - He is not evil.
这是命令，医生
I gave you an order, doctor.
你应该早点动手，詹姆士
You should've killed me while you could, James.
指令和怜悯使人成为笨蛋
Command and compassion is a fool's mixture.
我也被某种力量袭击了
It hit me too, whatever it was.
科尔索死了，是被勒死的
Kelso is dead, strangled.
至少史波克还活着
At least Spock's alive.
- 德纳医生呢？ - 她和米歇尔走了
- Dr. Dehner? - She went with Mitchell.
等我走了再给他吃药
Don't give him a pill until after I'm gone.
米歇尔变成这样是我的错
My fault Mitchell got as far as he did.
你看到他们去哪了吗？
Did you see their direction?
是的，怎么了？当时还有些晨光
Why, yes. There was some morning light.
我看见他们穿过山谷，往山峰左边去了
They were headed across the valley to the left of the pointed peaks.
- 好的 - 那些山峰后面有平原
- Yes. - There's flatlands beyond.
史波克先生醒过来之后
When Mr. Spock recovers,
你们要马上传送回进取号
you'll both transport up immediately to the Enterprise.
但是，舰长--
But, captain--
如果你们在12小时之内没收到我的信号…
Where, if you have not received a signal from me within 12 hours...
…就以最高曲速前往最近的地球基地
...you'll proceed at maximum warp to the nearest Earth base
并以我的名义…
with my recommendation...
…告诉他们，这个星球
...that this entire planet be subjected
存在着致命的氘辐射
to a lethal concentration of deuteron radiation.
不准违抗我的命令，马克
No protest on this, Mark. That's an order.
如果这里能出现生物，那真是个奇迹
It would take almost a miracle to survive here.
那就由我来创造这个奇迹
Well, then, I shall make one.
看
Behold.
你很快就能体会到了，伊丽莎白
You'll soon share this feeling, Elizabeth.
身为神的感觉
To be like God.
拥有随意创造世界的力量
To have the power to make the world anything you want it to be.
怎么了？
What's wrong?
有人来了
A visitor.
一个非常愚蠢的人
A very foolish man.
你会喜欢上这感觉的，伊丽莎白
You'll enjoy being a god, Elizabeth.
亵渎神明吗？不
Blasphemy? No.
要有食物
Let there be food.
卡菲里安苹果
Kaferian apples.
那个星球最令我喜欢的就是这些苹果
Whenever we visited that planet, I always favoured these.
你听到了吗，詹姆士？
Can you hear me, James?
你看不到我的，我不在那里
You cannot see me. I'm not there.
詹姆士，如果你选对了路，很快就能找到我
You follow the right path, James. You'll come to me soon.
我也通过意念看到他了
I can see him in my mind too.
去找他，伊丽莎白
Go to him, Elizabeth.
跟他谈谈
Talk to him.
既然你已蜕变，就去感受下他们是多么微不足道吧
Now that you're changing, I want you to see just how unimportant they are.
没错，我蜕变得有点慢
Yes, it just took a little longer for it to happen to me.
你必须帮助我
You must help me.
现在还不晚
Before it goes too far.
他是为我们两个好
What he's doing is right, for him and me.
那么对全人类来说呢？
And for humanity?
你还是人类，至少有一部分是！
You're still human, at least partly you are!
否则我们就不会在这里说话
Or you wouldn't be here talking to me.
地球根本微不足道
Earth is really unimportant.
很快，我们就会超越
Before long, we'll be where it would have taken mankind
人类文明数百万年
millions of years of learning to reach.
米歇尔能从中学到什么？
And what will Mitchell learn on getting there?
他会懂得如何运用他的力量吗？
Will he know what to do with his power?
- 他能获得智慧吗？ - 趁现在赶紧走吧
- Will he acquire the wisdom? - Please go back while you still can.
你听到他把怜悯当做笑话吗？
Did you hear him joke about compassion?
身为神，最重要的就是有一颗怜悯之心！
Above all else, a god needs compassion!
米歇尔！
Mitchell!
- 伊丽莎白 - 你根本不明白身为神的感受
- Elizabeth. - What do you know about gods?
那我们来谈谈人类
Then let's talk about humans.
谈谈我们的缺点
About our frailties.
即使他法力无边，仍然有人类的缺点
As powerful as he gets, he'll still have all that inside of him.
回去吧
Go back.
你曾是精神病学专家
You were a psychiatrist once.
你知道我们内心都深藏着丑陋和残暴
You know the ugly, savage things we all keep buried,
只是我们不敢表现出来
that none of us dare expose.
但他会，那谁去阻止他？
But he'll dare. Who's to stop him?
他根本不会在乎
He doesn't need to care.
做回一个心理医生吧，就一分钟
Be a psychiatrist for one minute longer.
你觉得他会怎样？
What do you see happening to him?
你的诊断结果是什么，医生？
What's your prognosis, doctor?
他来了
He's coming.
那就看着他
Then watch him.
再保持一下人类的理智！
Hang on to being a human for one minute longer!
我对你很失望，伊丽莎白
I'm disappointed in you, Elizabeth.
我一直在想象老友死去的场面
I've been contemplating the death of an old friend.
但至少，他得有个体面的坟墓
He deserves a decent burial, at least.
（詹姆士·寇克，1277.1-1313.7）
住手，加里
Stop it, Gary.
道德只对人类有意义，对神毫无意义
Morals are for men, not gods.
一个神
A god...
仍受到人性丑恶驱使的神
...but still driven by human frailty.
你喜欢这一切吗？
Do you like what you see?
祈祷吧，舰长
Time to pray, captain.
向我祈祷
Pray to me.
向你祈祷？不是向你们两个吗？
To you? Not to both of you?
祈求死得痛快吧
Pray that you die easily.
说到底，一山容不得二虎
There'll only be one of you in the end.
一个充满嫉妒之心的神
One jealous god.
你究竟是成了神，还是别的什么东西？
If all this makes a god. Or is it making you something else?
最后一次机会，寇克
Your last chance, Kirk.
你喜欢这一切吗？
Do you like what you see?
绝对权力产生绝对腐败？
Absolute power corrupting absolutely?
抓紧
Hurry.
时间不多了
You haven't much time.
加里，原谅我
Gary, forgive me.
机不可失啊，詹姆士
For a moment, James...
失不再来了
...but your moment is fading.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
你不明白这种…
You can't know what it's like...
…几乎成神的感觉
...to be almost a god.
呼叫进取号
Enterprise...
这是寇克舰长
...from Captain Kirk.
请回答
Come in.
舰长日志，星历1313.8
Captain's log, stardate 1313.8.
我们失去了伊丽莎白·德纳医生
Add to official losses Dr. Elizabeth Dehner.
但请铭记她为她的职责所献出的生命
Be it noted she gave her life in performance of her duty.
还有加里·米歇尔上尉…
Lieutenant Commander Gary Mitchell...
也请记住他的贡献
...same notation.
我希望他的服役记录能以这样的方式结束
I want his service record to end that way.
他也没料到会发生这种事
He didn't ask for what happened to him.
我也很同情他
I felt for him too.
我相信你还是有救的，史波克先生
I believe there's some hope for you after all, Mr. Spock.
本集结束
-=The Last Fantasy=-
谢谢观赏